<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>

   <properties>
      <title>Json-lib::Advanced Features</title>
   </properties>

   <body>
      <section name="Advanced Features">
         <subsection name="Transforming key names">
            The
            <a href="http://json.org">JSON spec</a>
            states that an object key is a String and
            <blockquote>
               A string is a collection of zero or more Unicode
               characters, wrapped in double quotes, using backslash
               escapes. A character is represented as a single character
               string. A string is very much like a C or Java string.
            </blockquote>
            This means that you may have a valid JSON key but and invalid Java identifier
            when transforming form JSON to Java. In order to avoid this problem, Json-lib
            defines a set of helpers of type JavaIdentifierTransformer that will handle
            the following cases:<ul>
            <li>JavaIdentifierTransformer.NOOP - will perform no transformation.</li>
            <li>JavaIdentifierTransformer.STRICT - will throw JSONException if a non JavaIdentifier character is found.</li>
            <li>JavaIdentifierTransformer.CAMEL_CASE - will use non JavaIdentifier and whitespace characters as word boundaries, 
            capitalizing the first char of a new word.</li>
            <li>JavaIdentifierTransformer.WHITESPACE - will trim all whitespace and non JavaIdentifier characters from the input string.</li>
            <li>JavaIdentifierTransformer.UNDERSCORE - will transform all whitespace and non JavaIdentifier characters to '_'.</li>
            </ul>You may also create and register your own JavaIdentifierTransformers using <tt>JsonConfig.setJavaIdentifierTransformer()</tt>
         </subsection>
         
         <subsection name="Build events">
         You may recieve events while building an object with the JSONSerializer or the static builder <tt>fromObject</tt> of 
         JSONObject&amp;JSONArray, all you have to do is enabled event triggering on JsonConfig. The following is a list of events
         generated by the build process: start/end (object), start/end (array), propertySet( object), elementAdd (array), warning, error.
         </subsection>
         
         <subsection name="Skipping transient fields">
         When building a JSONObject with <tt>fromObject</tt> or with the JSONSerializer you may skip all transient fields of the source
         bean, provided that the name of the property returned from the PropertyDescriptor matches the name of the field, meaning that
         this option will not work if you have a BeanInfo that changes the name of a read method or provides a synthetic property.
         </subsection>
      </section>
   </body>
</document>