<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>

   <properties>
      <title>Json-lib::Feature List</title>
   </properties>

   <body>
      <section name="Feature List">
         <p>The following is a list of the most notable features available in Json-lib.
         </p>
         <subsection name="Java">
          <p>The following options are configurable with JsonConfig:
          <ul>
          <li>bidirectional serialization, supports Maps, Collections, arrays (primitives, multidimensional), beans, DynaBeans, Enums &amp; Annotations (jdk15 package only)</li>
          <li>supports custom serialization with 3 schemes:<ul>
                <li>the bean implements JSONString interface</li>
                <li>register a JsonBeanProcessor for the whole bean</li>
                <li>register a JsonValueProcessor for a bean property (key and/or type)</li>
          </ul></li>
          <li>register a DefaultValueProcessor for returning a default value when a null reference is encountered</li>
          <li>plugin your own strategy for selecting a JsonBeanProcessor with JsonBeanProcessorMatcher</li>
          <li>plugin your own strategy for selecting a DefaultValueProcessor with DefaultValueProcessorMatcher</li>
          <li>modify the target property name when transforming from JSON to Java if the name is not a valid JavaIdentifier</li>
          <li>skip modifying map keys when transforming form JSON to Java if the key is not a valid JavaIdentifier</li>
          <li>register your own JavaIdentifierTransformer strategy</li>
          <li>publish events when building a JSONObject or JSONarray. The available events are:<ul>
             <li>object start/end</li>
             <li>array start/end</li>
             <li>propertySet</li>
             <li>elementAdded</li>
             <li>warning (recoverable)</li>
             <li>error (exception)</li>
          </ul></li>
          <li>Cycle detection, there are two default strategies (default throws an exception), you can register your own</li>
          <li>Skip transient fields when serailizing to JSON (default=don't skip)</li>
          <li>Exclude bean properties and/or map keys when serailizing to JSON (default=['class','metaClass','declaringClass'])</li>
	  <li>Filters provide a finer detail for excluding/including properties when serializing to JSON or transforming back to Java</li>
          <li>plugin your own strategy for instatiating beans if they do now follow the no-args constructor rule</li>
          <li>JSONObject implements java.util.Map and java.util.Comparable</li>
          <li>JSONArray implements java.util.List and java.util.Comparable</li>
          <li>JSONObject, JSONArray and JSONNull implement a base interface: JSON</li>
          <li>JSONAssert, a test-friendly class for testing JSON values</li>
          </ul>
          </p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="XML">
            <p>The following options are configurable in XMLSerializer:
            <ul>
               <li>[read] trim leading and trailing whitespace from element values</li>
               <li>[read] skip namespace handling</li>
               <li>[read] trim namespace prefixes</li>
               <li>[write] skip reading type hints (useful for converting back to JSON)</li>
               <li>[write] write type hints (useful for converting back to JSON)</li>
               <li>[write] skip writing type hints (useful for converting back to JSON)</li>
               <li>[write] change default values for Object, Array and Element tag names</li>
               <li>[write] change default value for Root element tag name</li>
               <li>[write] raise error if namespace uri is missing</li>
               <li>[write] transform an explicit array into an implicit array</li>
            </ul>
            </p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Web">
            <p>The following options are configurable in WebUtils:
            <ul>
               <li>do not output quotes for object keys when its safe for JavaScript</li>
               <li>two default strategies for preventing javascript hijacking, you can register your own</li>
            </ul>
            </p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Groovy">
            <ul>
               <li>support for the leftshift ( &lt;&lt; ) operator in JSONObject</li>
               <li>support for the spaceship ( &lt;=&gt; ) and its cousins</li>
               <li>type conversion with the <code>as</code> keyword</li>
               <li>a Groovy JSON builder</li>
            </ul>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="JRuby">
            <ul>
               <li>JSONArray.empty? is an alias for JSONArray.isEmpty()</li>
               <li>JSONObject.empty? is an alias for JSONObject.isEmpty()</li>
               <li>support for the leftshift ( &lt;&lt; ) operator in JSONObject</li>
            </ul>
         </subsection>
      </section>
   </body>
</document>
