<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>

    <properties>
        <title>Json-lib::Groovy integration</title>
    </properties>

    <body>
        <section name="Using Json-lib with Groovy">
            <p>
                <center>
                    <a href="http://groovy.codehaus.org">
                        <img src="images/logos/groovy-logo.png"/>
                    </a>
                </center>
            </p>
            <p>Since version 2.0 Json-lib has integrated
                <a href="http://groovy.codehaus.org">Groovy</a>
                support, meaning that POGOs can be transformed into JSON and back, in the same manner as you do now with POJOs. There are other features as well:
                <ul>
                    <li>Type transformations with the
                        <tt>as</tt>
                        keyword.
                        <br/>
                        A Groovy List (default type is ArrayList) can be transformed into a JSONArray.
                        <br/>
                        A Groovy Map (default type is HashMap) can be transformed into a JSONObject.
                        <br/>
                        A String can be transformed into JSON, JSONObject, JSONArray and JSONFunction.
                        <br/>
                        <textarea cols="70" rows="4" class="groovy:nocontrols:nogutter" name="srccode">
                            def fromList = [1,true,'json'] as JSONarray
                            def fromMap = [integer:1, bool: true] as JSONObject
                            def strAsJson1 = "{integer:1, bool: true}" as JSON
                            def strAsJson2 = "[1,2,3]" as JSON
                            def strAsJsonObject = "{integer:1, bool: true}" as JSONObject
                            def strAsJsonArray = "[1,2,3]" as JSONArray
                            def strAsFunc = "function(param){ this.param = param; }" as JSONFunction
                        </textarea>
                    </li>
                    <li>JSONObject supports the leftShift (&lt;&lt;) operator to append values, the following rules apply:
                        <ul>
                            <li>If the shifted arg is a Map, it will call putAll() on the object.</li>
                            <li>If the shifted arg is a List and its size == 2, the first element will be the key, and the second will be the value.</li>
                            <li>If the shifted arg is a List and its size > 2, the first element will be the key, the arg will be shifted by 1 and passed as the value (will create a JSONArray because it is a List).</li>
                            <li>Any other type will be discarded, the object will not be affected nor an exception will be thrown.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>JSONObject and JSONarray implement java.util.Comparable, which enables the use of the comparison operators with them (including the spaceship operator).</li>
                    <li>JSONObject implements java.util.Map and JSONArray implements java.util.List, anything you can do with Maps and List can be done with JSONObject and JSONArray.</li>
                    <li>JsonGroovyBuilder behaves like the JsonBuilder found in Grails but it will create a JSONObject/JSONArray instead of writing the built structure into a String.</li>
                </ul>
                <p>
                    <center>
                        <table>
                            <td valign="middle">
                                <img src="images/icon_warning_sml.gif"/>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <strong>
                                    <font color="#FF0000">CAUTION:</font>
                                    Since version 2.2.1 Json-lib will not automatically enhance class through custom metaclasses, you must call GJson.enhanceClasses() before executing the examples shown on this page.
                                </strong>
                            </td>
                            <td valign="middle">
                                <img src="images/icon_warning_sml.gif"/>
                            </td>
                        </table>
                    </center>
                </p>
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
