<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>

    <properties>
        <title>Json-lib::Who is using it</title>
    </properties>

    <body>
        <section name="Who is using it ?">
            <p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <th>Project</th>
                        <th>Description</th>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <td valign="top" align="center">
                                <a href="http://www.mentaframework.org/">Mentawai</a>
                            </td>
                            <td valign="top">The Mentawai goal is to be a simple, flexible, joyful and productive Java web framework.
                                <br/>
                                Json-lib is used in the AJAX renderers package. Thanks to Rubem Azenha.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td valign="top" align="center">
                                <a href="https://springmodules.dev.java.net/">
                                    <img src="https://springmodules.dev.java.net/images/icon.gif" alt="Spring Modules"
                                         border="0"/>
                                </a>
                            </td>
                            <td valign="top">Spring Modules is a collection of tools, add-ons and modules to extend the
                                <a href="http://www.springframework.org">Spring Framework</a>. The core goal of
                                Spring Modules is to facilitate integration between Spring and other projects
                                without cluttering or expanding the Spring core.
                                <br/>
                                Json-lib is used in the XT AJAX Framework. Thanks to Sergio Bossa.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td valign="top" align="center">
                                <a href="http://maven.nuxeo.org/">Nuxeo</a>
                            </td>
                            <td valign="top">Nuxeo 5 is a robust, extensible, global Enterprise Content Management (ECM) solution
                                available as Open Source Software.
                                <br/>
                                Json-lib is used in the NXThemes JSF components module. Thanks to Jean-Marc Orliagueta.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td valign="top" align="center">
                                <a href="http://ejoe.sourceforge.net/">EJOE</a>
                            </td>
                            <td valign="top">EJOE is a lightweight Java client/server framework built to send and receive objects
                                through pluggable (de)serialization mechanisms. It offers a high-performance, simple, and
                                clean object request broker (whereby ORB is meant in its natural manner and not in its
                                relation with CORBA), with server and client components for easy integration in your
                                client/server applications. It's an highly scaleable implementation of the common
                                request-process-response pattern based on the java.nio package.
                                <br/>
                                Json-lib is used in the JSON adpaters package. Thanks to Michael Manske.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td valign="top" align="center">
                                <a href="http://incubator.apache.org/ofbiz/">Apache OFBiz</a>
                            </td>
                            <td valign="top">The Open For Business Project is an open source enterprise automation software project
                                licensed under the Apache License Version 2.0. By open source enterprise automation we mean:
                                Open Source ERP, Open Source CRM, Open Source E-Business / E-Commerce, Open Source SCM,
                                Open Source MRP, Open Source CMMS/EAM, and so on.
                                <br/>
                                Thanks to Si Chen.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td valign="top" align="center">
                                <a href="http://www.opentaps.org/">opentaps</a>
                            </td>
                            <td valign="top">opentaps Open Source ERP + CRM brings you the advanced features and power of Tier 1 ERP
                                and CRM software with the flexibility and low cost of ownership that only open source can deliver.
                                You can use opentaps as an alternative to expensive and inflexible commercial ERP solutions, as a
                                replacement for in-house solutions that are difficult to maintain or extend, or as a starting point
                                to build your unique business model and processes.
                                <br/>
                                opentaps is powered by OFBiz. Thanks to Si Chen.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td valign="top" align="center">
                                <a href="http://incubator.apache.org/tuscany/">Apache Tuscany</a>
                            </td>
                            <td valign="top">The aim of the Apache Tuscany project is to create, as a community, a robust
                                infrastructure that simplifies the development of SOA-based systems. This project is currently
                                in incubation within the Apache incubator.
                                <br/>
                                Json-lib is used for testing purpouses in the bindings/jsonrpc module.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td valign="top" align="center">
                                <a href="http://www.azuki-framework.org/wiki/index.php?title=Main_Page">Azuki Framework</a>
                            </td>
                            <td valign="top">The Azuki framework is a Java application framework including many features (dependency, AOP,
                                Event-based processing....) and provides a visual tool that describes your software architecture.
                                <br/>
                                Json-lib is used on the server-side with Azuki beans. Thanks to Mathieu Jucker.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <!--<td valign="top" align="center"><a href="http://code.google.com/p/pimpas/">Pimpas Framework</a></td>-->
                            <td valign="top" align="center">
                                <a href="http://www.pimpas.net">Pimpas Framework</a>
                            </td>
                            <td valign="top">Pimpas Framework its a cool framework that help people to play with Java. We hav security using JAAS,
                                xml reader provide by dom4j, web container provider by tomcat, using jsf to create visual components for web.
                                Our framework its simple and fast.
                                <br/>
                                Json-lib is used in the javascript transformation module. Thanks to Casmeiron.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td valign="top" align="center">
                                <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/salto-framework">Salto Framework</a>
                            </td>
                            <td valign="top">Salto framework is an AJAX based framework which makes possible to build a Web application
                                very quickly. Thanks to AJAX mechanism, datas exchanges between client side an server side are reduced. You are able
                                to refresh only a part of the screen.
                                <br/>
                                Json-lib is used in Tree-rendering components. Thanks to Jerome Denolf.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr>
                            <td valign="top" align="center">
                                <a href="http://www.mulesource.org/display/JIRA/Home">Mule JIRA Transport</a>
                            </td>
                            <td valign="top">JIRA Transport is a transport provider that allows your Mule and other integrated services to communicate
                                with one or more JIRA systems easily.
                                <br/>
                                Json-lib is used to transform JSON objects into XML and Java. Thanks to Yuen Chi Lian.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <th>Company</th>
                        <th>Description</th>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <td valign="top" align="center">
                                <a href="http://www.tietoenator.com/">
                                    <img src="http://www.tietoenator.com/images/tietoenator.gif" alt="TietoEnator"
                                         border="0"/>
                                </a>
                            </td>
                            <td valign="top">The largest IT-services company in Scandinavia is consulting, developing and hosting its
                                customers digital businesses. TietoEnator is among the leading architects in building a more
                                efficient information society. With over 15 000 experts, it is one of the largest IT services
                                providers in Europe.
                                <br/>
                                Json-lib is used in an undisclosed project. Thanks to Manish Shah.
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
            </p>
            <p>If you'd like your project included in this list, please send a message to
                <a href="http://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/json-lib-user">Json-lib's User list</a>.
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
